# MARCELLA GARCIA

www.linkedin.com/in/marcellits | github.com/marcellits | www.marcellagarcia.com | Miami, FL

#### **TECH SKILLS**

JavaScript, React.js, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, API, Git, GitHub, MongoDB, Mongoose, Express, Node.js, Test Driven Development - TDD, Jest, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop, Microsoft Excel, Trello, Kanban.

#### **INTERPERSONAL SKILLS**

Problem-solving, Learn fast, Curious, Active Listening, Teamwork, Diligent, Organized, Humor, Portuguese native speaker, Spanish, and English speaker.

# **PROJECTS**

#### **Next Tech Trivia**

Next Tech Trivia is an interactive game for Google Cloud Next '20: OnAir. Our amazing team developed a dynamic app so the user can enjoy an awesome experience! If the user answers 4-5 questions correctly, the user can spin the wheel for a prize! This project is coded in Javascript + MERN Stack. To build a spin wheel, we applied Canvas. We also used 3 APIs: Gitfit as rewards, SendGrid to send emails to users, and Cloudinary to store images.

## **SmartAgenda**

SmartAgenda is a web application for business owners to keep track of client information as well as appointments that are displayed on their calendar. Javascript, MERN Stack, and Mongoose were used to develop this project and used FullCalendar.io library, Moment.js, and React Date-Picker in the frontend. This project is under continuous improvement for the next releases.

# **Easy Weather**

Easy Weather is a React app that pulls weather information from WeatherAPI.com. Javascript, Express, and Node.js were used to develop this project. To manipulate date and time we used Moment.js and to stylize we used React Bootstrap, such as Button and Cards to display the forecast. Also, we used a typewriter effect on the home page, handling CSS properties to display it.

## **EXPERIENCE**

## Full Stack Web Developer Wyncode Academy | April 2020 - June 2020

- Client-side: Trained in JavaScript, CSS, HTML, web frameworks and libraries, such as React.js, Bootstrap, React Bootstrap, Moment, and FullCalendar.io; and experience using APIs.
- **Server-side and database:** Trained in setting the backend environment utilizing MERN stack (MongoDB, Express, React, and Node.js).
- Managing tasks: experience with Kanban method as a work management system using Trello as a tool.

#### **Supervisor** Presidency of the Republic of Brazil | September 2013 - May 2019

Member of Permanent Bidding and Procurement Commission, acting as an auctioneer in more than 120 public biddings, dealing with procurement procedures and administrative member of Information Technology Contracts Commission.

# **Bank Teller** Banco do Brasil | May 2010 - September 2013

Customer Service, providing account services to customers such as deposits and loan payments; bill payments, cashing checks; issuing savings withdrawals; doing transfer bank to bank, doing judicial deposits, etc.

#### **Assistant** Ministry of Fishing and Aquaculture (Brazil) | February 2007 - April 2010

Working as an assistant in the Public Relations department, my position required organizing events and promotion of MPA events through email marketing. My team organized more than 50 events through these three years including one national, with more than 2.500 participants.

# **EDUCATION**

Wyncode Academy - 2020 - Full Stack Web Developer

**Inferir Estatistica -** 2019 - Statistics using Python (basics)

Centro Universitário IESB

2016-2017 - Master degree - Public Administration 2008-2012 - Bachelor degree - Publicity and Advertising